Guide to Miscellaneous Financial Materials Concerning Farm Corporations Operating in the North American West
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Miscellaneous financial materials concerning farm corporations operating in the North American West
1864-1936
Ndy10
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(2 boxes)
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning agricultural companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence; notices and letters to the stock- and bondholders; company profiles; by-laws; reports on company finances, operations and facilities; prospectuses; subscription agreements; proxy statements; mortgage indentures; bondholders' agreements; reorganization plans and agreements; funding plans and agreements and refinancing agreements. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Most of these financial materials were part of a collection acquired by Yale in 1922 from William H. Brown of West Haven, Conn. The collection, initially called the William H. Brown Statistical Library, numbered some 23,000 documents and covered the years 1890 to 1917. The collection was merged with similar materials already in the University Library and later expanded by gifts from Brown and others to become what is now known as the William H. Brown Collection.
Scope and Contents
This collection, compiled by William H. Brown, contains a variety of financial documents concerning agricultural companies operating in the North American West. Examples of these documents include company correspondence; notices and letters to the stock- and bondholders; company profiles; by-laws; reports on company finances, operations and facilities; prospectuses; subscription agreements; proxy statements; mortgage indentures; bondholders' agreements; reorganization plans and agreements; funding plans and agreements and refinancing agreements. While all of these documents are represented in the collection, they are not all represented by each company.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically by company name.
Farm corporations -- United States; Proxy statements -- Specimens.; Financial statements -- Specimens.; William H. Brown Collection
- Aztec Land and Cattle Company, Limited, 1885-1927; Ndy10 Az8; (5 documents) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- California Delta Farms, Incorporated, 1928-1929; Ndy10 +C115; (3 documents) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Colorado Fuel and Iron Company, 1893-1936; Ndy10 +C719; (15 documents) (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  Scope and Contents
  Included is a 53-page, journal-style report in typescript from 1902 by J.A. Potter on the properties of the Colorado Fuel and Iron Company.
- Idaho Irrigation Company, Limited, 1908; Ndy10 +Id2; (3 documents) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Jersey Island Company, 1907; Ndy10 +J48; (1 document) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Laguna Valley Company, 1895; Ndy10 +L13; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Mill City and Water Company, 1864; Ndy10 M61; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Mississippi River Delta Corporation, 1916; Ndy10 +M69; (2 documents) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- National Land and Irrigation Company, 1896; Ndy10 N21; (1 document) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Natomas Consolidated of California, 1911-1914; Ndy10 +N23; (2 documents) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Netherlands Farms Company, 1916; Ndy10 N38; (2 documents) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- New Mexico Land and Irrigation Company, 1894; Ndy10 N42; (3 documents) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Oregon Improvement Company, 1880-1896; Ndy10 Or3; (11 documents) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Valier-Montana Land & Water Company, 1913; Ndy10 +V22; (2 documents) (Box 2, Folder 9)